Guide to the Christopher Knowles Papers, 1973-2015 (bulk 1973-1990) MSS.414
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XI: Data Storage, tbd; 275955
  - Chris Knowles' Books Disk #1 Stills, undated; 276350 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0007)
  - Chris Knowles' Books #2 Stills, undated; 276351 (Box 19, Item ID: 4141.3.0008)
  - Chris Knowles' Books Disk #3 Stills, undated; 276352 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0009)
  - Christopher Knowles Archive, January 2002; 276353 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0010)
  - Christmas 2000, 276354 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0011)
  - Christopher Knowles '77 Maplethorpe [sic], undated; 276355 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0012)
- Series XIV: Books, 1973-2011; 2 Linear Feet 2 record cartons.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains several volumes donated with the collection.
  - Checkpoint Charley, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Dworkin, Craig, and Kenneth Goldsmith. Against Expression, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Esopus 20: Special Collections (Fall 2013) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Glass, Philip. Music by Philip Glass, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Hindsight May 1976-April 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ibsen, Henrik. When We Dead Awaken, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Knowles, Christopher. Drawings, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Knowles, Christopher. Typings (1974-1977) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Kotik, Charlotta and Tumelo Mosaka. Open House: Working in Brooklyn, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Live: Performance Art 1, 2, 4, 5, 6/7, 1979-1982 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - MuseumJournaal No. 26/2, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Of Mice and Men, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Of Mice and Men: Exhibition Guide, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Rattemeyer, Christian. The Judith Rothschild Foundation Contemporary Drawings Collection: Catalogue Raisonne, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Robert Wilson o il teatro del tempo, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Roof VI: 27 poems by 18 poets, Spring 1978 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Shyer, Laurence. Robert Wilson and his Collaborators, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - So & So Fall 1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - St. Mark's Church Poetry and Danspace Projects Eye and Ear Theater, Inc. A Tribute to Edwin Denby, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Two Conversations with Edwin Denby, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Valencia 09/Confines, 2009 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Unmuzzled Ox vol. IV no. 3, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Robert. 14 Stations, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, Robert. 70 Angels on the Façade: Domus 1928-1998 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The World #31, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- OVERSIZE: Series I, 274431
  - Clubs Spades Diamonds Hearts, May 1974; 274475 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Sundance Kid, April 1974; 274476 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 13 Chapters, January-February, 1975; 274477 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Song List], c. 1972; 275064 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Dialog/Curious George], c. 1979; 275065 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Happy 28th Birthday..., May 1987; 274478 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - [20 Faces in Pen...], c. 1988; 274479 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Book II, undated; 274480 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Brother, Sister, Mother, Father..., undated; 274481 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - This is Christopher's Book & At the Beach Book, undated; 274482 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - This Magic Moment..., undated; 274483 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE: Series II, 274432
  - Subseries A: Performances with Christopher Knowles, 275155
    - $ Value of Man Poster, 1975; 275148 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Avalance "Because Why" with Bob Wilson, 1975; 275149 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - De Hoek Van de Straat 5 "Dialog/Network", 1976; 275150 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Emily Likes the TV Poster, undated; 275151 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Knot I Land Poster & Program, undated; 275152 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - A Letter for Queen Victoria, undated; 275153 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Mehdi Khonsari Photos of "A Mad Man, A Mad Dog...", 1974; 275154 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Dialog/Curious George Poster, 1980; 275209 (Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Performances without Christopher Knowles, 275156
    - Byrd Hoffman School of Byrds Programs, 1972, undated; 275157 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Riding the Right Horse Poster, August 1979; 275158 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- OVERSIZE: Series III, 274433
  - Gavin Brown's Enterprise Posters, 2004; 275162 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 4 Typings Shown at Gladstone Gallery, 2006; 275163 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE: Series IV, 274434
  This series contains three bags of color paper cut outs used by Knowles in an exhibit at the Museum Boymans in Rotterdamn. They are listed here as folders 1 through 4 in box 15.
  - Portraits of Christopher by "K.K.", 1974; 275164 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Paris Self-Service Story, undated; 275165 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - All About Me Book, Song list, 1972, undated; 275169 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - David Hatchett Parzival Watercolor, 1988; 275170 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - History of My Memories, 1988; 275171 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Get lost Artists Map Downtown New York, c. 2007; 275173 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Bike Race Print, undated; 275174 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Clock Drawing, undated; 275175 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Drawings [1 of 2], undated; 275177 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Drawings [2 of2], undated; 275178 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - [Marker Drawing], undated; 275180 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - [Marker Drawings & Songs], undated; 275181 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - [Parzival, song list, birthday drawings], undated; 275182 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - [Pen Drawings], undated; 275183 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Red Ray Stevens, Green Glen Campbell, undated; 275185 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Ramsen Street Drawings, water colors and pen drawings, undated; 275186 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - [Years and Watercolors], undated; 275187 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Exit Art Labyrinth Wall Typing, February 2009; 275191 (Box 13)
  - Apples Peaches Pumpkin Pie Scroll, undated; 275192 (Box 14)
  - Paper cutouts used at Boymans Exhibit, undated; 275195 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Paper cutouts used at Boymans Exhibit, undated; 275196 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Paper cutouts used at Boymans Exhibit, undated; 275197 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Paper cutouts used at Boymans Exhibit, undated; 275198 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - I Got Rhythm, c. 1967; 275200 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sorry Seems to be the Hardest Word [Song titles], undated; 275203 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - [Yellow, Red, Green Crayon Drawing], undated; 275207 (Folder 6)
  - New York City's Top 101 of 1967 [Typing on Rice Paper], undated; 275208 (Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE: Series VI, 274439
  - Christopher Knowles & Bob Wilson Press, 1978, 1987; 275166 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - A Letter for Queen Victoria, 1974-1975; 275220 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - $ Value of Man press clippings, 1975; 275217 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Andy Warhol's Interview, 1976-1977; 275222 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Einstein on the Beach Village Voice, 1976; 275223 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - A Solo Performance SoHo Weekly News, 1976; 275224 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Art Communications Edition, 1977; 275225 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Emily Likes the TV news clippings, 1977; 275226 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - New York Post Drawing Center Exhibition, 1977; 275228 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Traveler's Digest Christopher Knowles/Cindy Lubar portrait, 1978; 275230 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Dialog/Curious George New York Times, 1978-1980; 275232 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - American Book Review of Typings, 1979; 275240 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - "Typings" Press Cards, 1979; 275241 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Art Forum, 1979, 2004; 275242 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Parzival New York Times, 1988; 275243 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Knot I Land Nashville Scene, 1990; 275244 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - La Tradicion Village Voice, 1997; 275245 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Art + Auction, 2003; 275246 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- OVERSIZE: Series VIII, 274441
  - Photo portrait of Christopher Knowles, undated; 275167 (Box 11, Folder 15)